<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="__TOPIC_66F09C4576FDEEC4" xml:lang="en-US">
	<title>DITA 1.2 element test</title>
	<prolog>
		<metadata>
			<keywords>
				<indexterm start="DITA_12_Testing_In_Metadata">DITA 1.2 Testing in &lt;metadata&gt;</indexterm>
			</keywords>
		</metadata>
	</prolog>
	<body>
	    <p id="p_01">The Darwin Information Typing Architecture (DITA) 1.2 specification defines a set of document types for
	        authoring and organizing topic-oriented information, as well as a set of mechanisms for combining, extending,
	        and constraining document types.</p>
	    <p>
	       The DITA 1.2 specification consists of the following components:</p>
	    <dl>
	        <dlentry>
	            <dt>Document Type Definitions (DTDs) and XML Schemas (XSDs)</dt>
	            <dd>The DTDs and XSDs – along with the catalog files – define DITA markup for the DITA vocabulary modules
	                and DITA document types. While the DTDs and XSDs should define the same DITA elements, the DTDs are
	                normative if there is a discrepancy. If there is a discrepancy between the written specification (this document)
	                and the DTDs, the written specification takes precedence.</dd>
	        </dlentry>
	        <dlentry>
	            <dt>DITA 1.2 written specification</dt>
	            <dd>While the DITA 1.2 documentation does contain some introductory information, it is intended neither as an
	                introduction to DITA nor as a users guide. The intended audience of this documentation consists of
	                implementers of the DITA standard, including tool developers and XML architects who develop
	                specializations. The documentation contains several parts:
	                <ul>
	                    <li>Architectural specification</li>
	                    <li>Language reference</li>
	                    <li>Conformance statement</li>
	                    <li>Appendices</li>
	                </ul>
	                The DITA 1.2 written specification is available in the following formats: XHTML, CHM, PDF, and DITA source.
	                The XHTML version is authoritative.</dd>
	        </dlentry>
	    </dl>
    </body>
</topic>
